Ty Mondragon

Longmont, CO 80501 ● (720) 401-6402 ● tymondragon@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 3 years of related experience.

Skills

- Elixir programming
- JavaScript programming

- Web-Based Software Engineering
- Code Reviews

Work History

Software Engineer, 06/2020 to Current

Roster - Longmont, Colorado

- Built with Elixir and Phoenix framework, with PostgreSQL data store.
- Built backend services using Elixir GenServer. Examples are notification systems for email, SMS, and Push.
- Integrated with 3rd party APIs such as SendGrid, Twilio, and Cloudinary.
- Used Docker and AWS, with Fargate for container orchestration.

Senior Full Stack Developer/Contractor, 01/2019 to Current

Indigo Education Company - Longmont, CO

- Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.
- Built with NodeJS runtime environment and Express library, with PostgreSQL database
- Built frontend user experience using Angular/Typescript framework.
- Integrated with 3rd party APIs such Sendgrid and TTI success insights and microservices.

Contract Frontend Developer, 10/2018 to 12/2018

Hive Network - Bouler, Colorado

- Developed user-oriented visuals and features using front-end languages, including Polymer3 and lit-element using GraphQl interface with MongoDB.
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.

Education

Certification: Software Engineering Immersive, 09/2018

Galvanize - Boulder, CO

Thrived in a comprehensive program that accelerates individuals to become Software Engineers. Worked independently and collaboratively to develop and deploy web applications by using Agile

development practices. Focused on computer science concepts, React.js, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS. Delivered on intense program requirements while enjoying the process of learning.

Bachelor of Arts: Fine Arts, 12/2002 **Colorado State University** - Fort Collins, CO

• Majored in Metalsmithing

Find Me

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/tymondragon
- https://github.com/tymondragon